<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My homepage on Osint For All</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My homepage on Osint For All</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arrays Are Powerful In Bash</title>
      <link>/linux/aib/aib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linux/aib/aib/</guid>
      <description>“$” might symbolize dollars to many of you, but for bash users it’s the holy grail for retrieving stored data. Speaking of which, do you know what’s the common place to store a piece of data? A variable.
Variable The name itself incurs that variable is something that could be varied. So is it like a chameleon that changes colors all the time? Not precisely, if you remember from the intro its a common place to store a piece of data.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;eye&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“$” might symbolize dollars to many of you, but for bash users it’s
the holy grail for retrieving stored data. Speaking of which, do you
know what’s the common place to store a piece of data? A variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name itself incurs that variable is something that could be
varied. So is it like a chameleon that changes colors all the time?
Not precisely, if you remember from the intro its a common place to
store a piece of data. That’s right. Mathematically and
computationally, a variable is something that stores or holds a
piece of data or value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have heard the term “place holder” and that’s exactly what
a variable is. So how to store and retrieve information through
variables?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;place=&amp;quot;World&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Hello $place&amp;quot; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above code snippet, place is a variable and World is the
value assigned to the variable. In the next line, the value assigned to the variable is retrieved through echo command. As
aforementioned, “$” is the holy grail to retrieve stored value in
bash. An important thing to note here is, “=” doesn’t mean variable
name has a constant value, it just means that a value is assigned to
a variable name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the value of variable place could be varied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;place=&amp;quot;Mars&amp;quot;
echo &amp;quot;Hello $place&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the value of variable has changed to Mars from World. Imagine a
box where you could place an item and replace that item whenever you
wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to store many pieces of data in a single box?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;array&#34;&gt;Array&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Array is an ordered series of arrangement. Computationally, array
holds multiple values, whereas a normal variable holds a single
value. Array could also be defined as a special type of variable as
it could hold more than one value.
A typical array consists of an array name and an index. Each index
number associates with an element in the array.
Lets see how to create an array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;movies=(&#39;Primer&#39; &#39;Inception&#39; &#39;Enemy&#39; &#39;Tenet&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two things to keep in mind. Unlike other programming languages, bash
arrays are not led by commas after every element but spaces. There
is no space after array name(i.e, movies=), it’s followed by “=”. If
there is a space followed by the array name, shell interprets the
array name as a program to execute and “=” as the first parameter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets try to retrieve all the elements of the array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the above screenshot, you could retrieve the
array elements in two ways: one using the @ symbol between the
square brackets or using * symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips, you could remember @ by memorizing it like all
and * is a wild card which signifies everything. The syntax of
retrieving an array could look intimidating, so always remember “$”
is the holy grail for retrieving information, array names are placed
in between flower brackets {}, followed by special characters or
numbers in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets see how to retrieve an individual element of the array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index numbers in bash arrays starts with 0 (similar to most of the
programming language, unlike R). So index 2 returns the value of
Enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s see what happens when negative indices are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the negative index number retrieves values from reverse order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could also assign elements to the array explicitly in three
ways: Subscript Assignment, Index Assignment and assignment by name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Subscript Assignment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;movies=([4]=&#39;Ten cloverfield lane&#39; [5]=&#39;Timecrimes&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/9.png&#34; alt=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Index Assignment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;movies[1]=&#39;Vanilla Sky&#39;
movies[2]=&#39;Mr.Nobody&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assignment by names&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;movies[zero]=&#39;Magnolia&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/11.png&#34; alt=&#34;11&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to print the elements from one particular index to
another?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/12.png&#34; alt=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you are telling the array that from all its elements(@) , print
from index 1 to index 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/13.png&#34; alt=&#34;13&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you are telling the array that from all its elements(@), start
from index 1 and print all the following elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if, you want to access the index numbers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;${!movies[@]}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/14.png&#34; alt=&#34;14&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “!” symbol before array name helps to retrieve indices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to see how many elements are there in an array?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;${#movies[@]}&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/15.png&#34; alt=&#34;15&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “#” symbol before array name helps to retrieve number of
elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to retrieve specific information from an element in the array?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/16.png&#34; alt=&#34;16&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the information of zeroth element(Magnolia) is retrieved,
starting from index 0 till index 2(not included).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to assign a sequence of numbers? You could do it
manually but here’s a easy way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/17.png&#34; alt=&#34;17&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;seq&lt;/em&gt; is a shell command that prints out sequence of numbers. In the
above example, &lt;em&gt;seq&lt;/em&gt; is placed in between ` `.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets try to write a simple shell script from the above
learnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/linux/AIB/usr/linux/AIB/bin/linux/AIB/bash
tvshows=(&#39;Mr.Robot&#39; &#39;Homeland&#39; &#39;The Americans&#39; &#39;Death Note&#39; &#39;Erased&#39;)
for a in &amp;quot;${!tvshows[@]}&amp;quot;; do
printf &amp;quot;${tvshows[$a]} has an index number of $a\n&amp;quot;
done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s save the code as lp.sh. Next lets make it executable – chmod
+x lp.sh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/18.png&#34; alt=&#34;18&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the program is executed, you get the above result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;array-modification&#34;&gt;Array Modification&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets create a new array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;names=(&#39;Luther&#39; &#39;Ambrose&#39; &#39;Reddington&#39; &#39;Mare&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;To change the value of index 2 you could do the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;names[2]=’Carrie’
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/19.png&#34; alt=&#34;19&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if, you want to append values by adding more elements to the
array?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/20.png&#34; alt=&#34;20&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if, you want to add an element at a particular index position?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/21.png&#34; alt=&#34;21&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to delete an element?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/22.png&#34; alt=&#34;22&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, unset is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiUoa6yh6v4AhXsSmwGHQMKDlMQFnoECAUQAQ&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FShell_builtin&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1BOf5zWyabXMcp7cEqn3O5&#34;&gt;shell builtin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/23.png&#34; alt=&#34;23&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to merge two arrays?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets create another array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;surnames=(&#39;Dexter&#39; &#39;Hannibal&#39; &#39;Broody&#39; &#39;Dan&#39; &#39;Gordan&#39; &#39;Steve&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/24.png&#34; alt=&#34;24&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to delete an array?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;unset &amp;lt;array_name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/25.png&#34; alt=&#34;25&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;associative-array&#34;&gt;Associative Array&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An associative array is an array that stores string value as an
index. It could be declared and used in a bash script. This feature
was added in bash 4. To be sure, just check your bash version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/26.png&#34; alt=&#34;26&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declaring an associative array is easy, here’s the syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;declare -A &amp;lt;array_name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lets declare an associative array and initialize some elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/27.png&#34; alt=&#34;27&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like in normal array, if you want to access an element of the array,
use the following syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/28.png&#34; alt=&#34;28&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to list the indices of the associative array, do the
following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/29.png&#34; alt=&#34;29&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets try to write a simple script to print the indices(keys) and
values of the associative array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/30.png&#34; alt=&#34;30&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a catch, what if you want to display the indices in an
alphabetic order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/31.png&#34; alt=&#34;31&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reverse it, use –reverse flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/linux/AIB/32.png&#34; alt=&#34;32&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that’s it for today. Do practice arrays; because they are
powerful! Show some love by sharing and subscribing to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCLi7utjkBxAYPtVQhTuiZ2Q&#34;&gt;Linux For All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case-1: Sarah</title>
      <link>/ctf/case1/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ctf/case1/1/</guid>
      <description>On October 24 2007, Sarah Gray, a Linguistics and Philosophy student from MIT disappears mysteriously. Her last email was sent to her friend. The subject said, “Hard to say…”, the body said, “I can’t say much right now, I can’t say what happened, I’m being watched, I’m going somewhere, where no one can find me, but I’ll be here somewhere. If you ever find me, say those words and I’ll know” and two PNG files were attached to the email.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;On October 24 2007, Sarah Gray, a Linguistics and Philosophy student from MIT disappears mysteriously. Her last email was sent to her friend. The subject said, “Hard to say…”, the body said, “I can’t say much right now, I can’t say what happened, I’m being watched, I’m going somewhere, where no one can find me, but I’ll be here somewhere. If you ever find me, say those words and I’ll know” and two PNG files were attached to the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/ctf/case1/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/ctf/case1/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you ever be able to ask her what happened?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case-2: Stampede</title>
      <link>/ctf/case2/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ctf/case2/2/</guid>
      <description>String Puller: Hello my lovely digital sleuths, our &amp;ldquo;Machine&amp;rdquo; is pointing us towards certain incidents from the past while performing a data analysis on a state sponsored cabal. So far we are not able to understand why it&amp;rsquo;s giving us these results. We tried to look for discrepancies or errors within our system, but surprisingly everything’s in the place and the information is relevant. So these results from the “Machine” should mean something, can you crack this?</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/ctf/case2/s.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;String Puller:&lt;/strong&gt; Hello my lovely digital sleuths, our &amp;ldquo;Machine&amp;rdquo; is pointing us towards certain incidents from the past while performing a data analysis on a state sponsored cabal. So far we are not able to understand why it&amp;rsquo;s giving us these results. We tried to look for discrepancies or errors within our system, but surprisingly everything’s in the place and the information is relevant. So these results from the “Machine” should mean something, can you crack this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results that we got are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1991: Orkney Stadium Disaster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2001: In Ghana, approximately 126 people were killed in a stampede at Accra’s main soccer stadium when police fired tear gas at rioting fans in one of Africa’s worst soccer disasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2005: Approximately 1,005 people die in Iraq when Shi’ites stampede off a bridge over the Tigris river in Baghdad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012: Port Said Stadium Disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2022: Riot at Indonesia soccer match kills 129.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck hunters.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Email Investigations – Accessibility And Limitations.</title>
      <link>/articles/email/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/email/email/</guid>
      <description>Even in the age of instant messaging apps, email still serves as an ‘official’ medium to communicate between two parties. It’s ironic that electronic mail has not lost its charm till date within the barrage of privacy respecting encrypted chat messengers.
Instead, email services nowadays are adapting to the new age norm of privacy and making their products more privacy hardened with encrypted mailboxes or hard to locate data centers and so on.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Even in the age of instant messaging apps, email still serves as an
‘official’ medium to communicate between two parties. It’s ironic
that electronic mail has not lost its charm till date within the
barrage of privacy respecting encrypted chat messengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, email services nowadays are adapting to the new age norm of
privacy and making their products more privacy hardened with
encrypted mailboxes or hard to locate data centers and so on. But
the core technology behind email hasn’t changed since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-steps&#34;&gt;First Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has become a tradition for any experienced or rookie
investigators to start their investigation just by ‘Googling’ stuff
out. Finding information about emails is no different, an email that
has to be investigated could be played around in a variety of forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw Email&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a plain email is put in the search bar, the results are limited
to the fact that how often that email has been used in public and
how open it is to the public. To simplify, if the email is used on
multiple blogs, academic websites, personal websites, social media,
paste bins, forums etc,. There is a strong chance of retrieving the
information about the keywords in the email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/email/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the above image, it’s evident that Google search engine
retrieved the information with some keywords involved within the
email. It recognized some keywords like ‘john’, ‘snow’, and ‘gmail’.
But it didn’t point towards the exact email; why? Because the exact
email wasn’t open for viewing in the wild. Interestingly it also
tried to match the keywords from different social media such as
Twitter and Pininterest. Endless scrolling and jumping to each page
might lead to the exact email or might not, and that’s the
limitation for the investigators and a slight win for privacy
settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding quotes around the email tells the search engine to look for
the exact keywords that’s specified within the quotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/email/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, with quotes the email led to one of the primary
sources of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, using quotes around an email tries to retrieve specific
information if it exists on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it? Is it that easy to retrieve information on anyone just by
Googling the email address? Well, the answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/email/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/email/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As aforementioned, Google or any search engines could retrieve the
information only if they are present on the internet. It depends on
a lot of factors such as one’s privacy settings, social engagement,
relevance, repeated usage of the same email, or being public and so
on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dorking&#34;&gt;Dorking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google dorking is an advanced way of searching results on the
internet. Other searching engines such as DuckDuckGo, Bing,
Startpage, Brave Search and so on could also be used for dorking.
Basically, dorking lets the user to concise the search results and
provide the accurate result as possible. And dorking is not only
limited to search engines, prominent social media platforms like
Twitter, Facebook, TikTok, Vkontakte etc,. have their own set of
dorks. Yet again, it depends on the information that’s already
available and privacy measures of the user. An article about
advanced search operators/dorks could be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://theamoghavarsha.medium.com/advanced-search-operators-1cb514c6cda8&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;potential-places-to-look-for-email&#34;&gt;Potential Places To Look For Email&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• Public Files – intext:”jack@twitter.com” filetype:pdf OR filetype:docx OR filetype:xls
• Leaked databases
• Online forums
• Academic websites
• Unfortunately, sometimes on medical websites
• Government websites
• Job search websites
• Automated tools
• Social media
• Chat apps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several tools on the internet that promise to provide much
more information about an email address than just Googling. A caveat
here is, those tools are also scraping the data from the internet
probably with better scraping methods and algorithms. These tools
also change every now and then, due to the changes made from the
product/service provider’s end (email) or changes made in their own
code(tools). And it’s not new to the OSINT community if some service
goes down or becomes redundant, there’ll always be new tools which
could be more or less efficient and that depends on various factors
that are discussed in the previous paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools to find information on emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://epieos.com/&#34;&gt;Epieos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hunter.io/email-finder&#34;&gt;Hunter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spiderfoot.net/&#34;&gt;SpiderFoot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maltego.com/&#34;&gt;Maltego&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anymailfinder.com/&#34;&gt;Anymailfinder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intelx.io/&#34;&gt;IntelligenceX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;miscellaneous-techniques&#34;&gt;Miscellaneous Techniques&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call it stalking or curiosity to know, some platforms such as Skype,
lets their users to search usernames or emails of other users. Even
in Gmail, some recommendations appear while one types an email for
the first time. Some apps also provide information about other users
when one’s contacts are synced. There could be many other apps out
there which provide a functionality to search for emails or
usernames. Another trick could be by changing language in inspect
element, or changing geographical location using proxies or VPNs to
fetch country specific results. Last but not the least, using the
power of other search engines and web scrapers along with Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;final-words&#34;&gt;Final Words&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email investigation through publicly available information is tricky
and prone to many false positives. This is because of the fact that
email service providers are becoming more closed to protect their
users’ privacy. And also, most of the search engines out there are
not &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_source&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;, it means no one knows how their algorithms work or how exactly they query information time to time and how a particular
information is queried. This is a challenge for many SEO experts and
email marketers to update themselves and understand how search
engines function and change overtime. There are dorks, but again
their use cases are limited. But the use of emails seems to not stop
anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzing With Good Old Radamsa</title>
      <link>/articles/radamsa/radamsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/radamsa/radamsa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;1337051nT&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;S3rlockedOSINTForall&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;oS$INTFOR@LL&amp;rdquo;
Did you know that Osint For All has many secret domain names? Just kidding, I don’t want to fuzz around any further, or maybe I do? So let’s jump in to the world of Radamsa.
Radamsa is a fuzzer. In technical terms, it is a test case generator for robustness testing. Typically, it is used to test how well a program could tolerate potentially malicious input. It works by reading files of valid data and generating random outputs every time from them.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;1337051nT&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;S3rlockedOSINTForall&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;oS$INTFOR@LL&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &lt;a href=&#34;https://osintforall.in/&#34;&gt;Osint For All&lt;/a&gt; has many secret domain names? Just
kidding, I don’t want to fuzz around any further, or maybe I do? So let’s jump in to the world of Radamsa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radamsa is a fuzzer. In technical terms, it is a test case generator
for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robustness_testing&#34;&gt;robustness testing&lt;/a&gt;. Typically, it is used to test how well a
program could tolerate potentially malicious input. It works by
reading files of valid data and generating random outputs every time
from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites – gcc, git, make, wget. If you are on Debian based
system just type:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install gcc git make wget
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The installation is pretty straight forward as the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://gitlab.com/akihe/radamsa.git &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd radamsa &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
sudo make install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;fuzzing&#34;&gt;Fuzzing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuzzing is messing around a program by supplying it with vague
inputs and see what happens. That’s where Radamsa comes into the
play. Testers have a brief idea about what should not happen and
they try to find that out. This referred to as negative testing,
opposite to integration testing. Developers try to write programs
which won’t crash, or consume lot of memory, whereas attackers try
to crash the program and try to exploit it if its vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radamsa is more of a black box fuzzer, meaning it doesn’t need
information about the program or the format of the data. It manages
to break the data in into interesting ways as it flows through a
program. Sometimes It could also generate more than one output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ways-to-fuzz-in-radamsa&#34;&gt;Ways To Fuzz In Radamsa&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data through pipes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;Anaesthesia&amp;quot; | radamsa
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number mutator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;Anaesthesia 1337&amp;quot; | radamsa --seed 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above example, Radamsa uses number mutation to change the
textual numbers with something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Outputs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using -n flag, multiple number of outputs could be generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;Anaesthesia 1337&amp;quot; | radamsa --seed 8 -n 4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about different options, use the man page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;man radamsa
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading input from standard input&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;bc&lt;/em&gt; is a language that supports arbitrary precision numbers with
interactive execution of
statements. xargs is used to execute commands from standard input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cat out radamsa!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s create a text file named l.txt and radamsit out and see if it
could give us a random password!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the content of l.txt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;radamsa l.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;After two iterations, radamsa generated a nice little string that
could be used as a password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating XSS payloads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuzzing with different file formats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As aforementioned, Radamsa could take in almost any file format and
give us a randomly generated string. So let’s compress l.txt to gzip
and see if radamsa could give us the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gzip l.txt
radamsa l.txt.gz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;radamsa-as-a-tcp-client&#34;&gt;Radamsa As A TCP Client&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radamsa is also capable of acting as a TCP client/server. So let’s
start a simple python server see if radamsa could connect to it. And
also let’s use the same l.txt.gz from the previous section as an
input file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;python3 -m http.server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;In another tab type the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;radamsa -o 0.0.0.0:8000 -v l.txt.gz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/radamsa/9.png&#34; alt=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tampering with software and then seeing it break and misbehave is a
delight to many hackers. Fuzzing is an art and Radamsa is one of the
powerful tools to add to your hacking toolkit. Many CVEs have been
discovered using Radamsa. Now go install Radamsa and fuzz the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPSEC For OSINT CTFs</title>
      <link>/articles/opsec/opsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/opsec/opsec/</guid>
      <description>CTFs (Capture The Flags) are a great way to enhance your skills. Whether it’s information security or Open Source Intelligence based CTFs, at the end of the day, they improve your problem solving abilities, and also, they are fun!
I started this tradition of making Twitter threads during TraceLabs’s CTF about OPSEC, especially focusing on judges using LOW END COMPUTERS. So I thought why not make a blog post about it so that everyone could benefit.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;CTFs (Capture The Flags) are a great way to enhance your skills. Whether it’s information security or Open Source Intelligence based CTFs, at the end of the day, they improve your problem solving abilities, and also, they are fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this tradition of making Twitter threads during TraceLabs’s CTF about OPSEC, especially focusing on judges using LOW END COMPUTERS. So I thought why not make a blog post about it so that everyone could benefit. I’m also going to add some extra insights which I couldn’t cover in those threads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;method-1&#34;&gt;Method 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a separate browser profile and delete it later. In Firefox based browsers, go to about:profiles and create one. In Chrome based browsers, you can find an option. And use User-Agent Switcher. Or you can also use Tor Browser(with/without a separate profile). Avoid installing addons or changing user agent strings while using Tor browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/opsec/1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/opsec/2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use browser based VPNs within the profile. (Not recommending any VPN in particular, choose one by researching a bit on the web, or probably the ones with good ratings, maximum users and past records)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If available use ‘trustable VPN of your choice’ on your main machine, along with browser vpn. A better way to make sure that your VPN is not leaking DNS is to test at - &lt;a href=&#34;http://dnsleaktest.com&#34;&gt;http://dnsleaktest.com&lt;/a&gt; after setting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use proxy chains (sudo apt install proxychains - for Debian based distros) and add public proxies down below in proxychains.conf, along with VPNs or use Tor proxy. Some privacy focused GNU/Linux distros, provide ‘anonymous mode’ or ‘tor mode’, use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/opsec/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;method-2&#34;&gt;Method 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Live/Persistent Bootable Pendrives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live bootable pendrive runs live on your device, that means, when you pull the pendrive out of your system, all your data will be gone. To make it effective, combine it with the instructions from &lt;strong&gt;Method 1.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On persistent bootable pendrives, you can allocate some space for storage and also encrypt that space. You can save your data and settings on persistent pendrives. When you pull out the pendrive from the system, nothing will be stored on your system’s hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Operating Systems For Bootable Pendrives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digi77.com/linux-kodachi/&#34;&gt;Kodachi OS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tsurugi-linux.org/&#34;&gt;Tsurugi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parrotsec.org/&#34;&gt;Parrot OS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kali.org/&#34;&gt;Kali&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I can’t create sock puppet accounts due to territorial restrictions and I can’t/don’t want to spend money on buying burners or temporary sim cards?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ans:&lt;/strong&gt; If the CTF is designed in a way, such that, you only need to verify the details of contestants&#39; submissions, then, you don’t need sock puppet accounts; simply follow the instructions from &lt;strong&gt;Method 1&lt;/strong&gt; or use the &lt;strong&gt;Tor browser&lt;/strong&gt; to do so. This applies only if the submissions are from social media platforms such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, and so on; where you can view the content from a “shared link” unless it’s public. If any of the social media sites require you to &lt;strong&gt;login/signup&lt;/strong&gt; for a second post from the same window, simply right-click on the link and open it in a &lt;strong&gt;private window&lt;/strong&gt;, which will fool the link into thinking that you are a different person/session accessing the link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Privacy Addons.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Agent Switcher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ublock Origin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy Badger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentraleyes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disconnect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghostery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook Container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Useful Addons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox Multi-Account Containers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session Box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can disable &lt;em&gt;Decentraleyes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt;, if they block the javascript from the website that you want to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all I got for today. This post will probably be updated once in a while. Keep learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah&#39;s Case Is Still Unsolved!</title>
      <link>/articles/unsolved1/unsolved1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/unsolved1/unsolved1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a month, and no one solved the case! Some came near, but went too far. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the beauty of The Unsolvable CTF?
As you have not solved the CTF yet (will you ever?😈), so here are some tips to approach the case.
First of all, ask yourself what have you got? A case file with 90 words and two images. That means, you have limited information and you have to start your investigation from there.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a month, and no one solved the case! Some came near, but went too far. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that the beauty of &lt;a href=&#34;https://osintforall.in/ctf/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Unsolvable CTF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you have not solved the CTF yet (will you ever?😈), so here are some tips to approach the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, ask yourself what have you got? A case file with 90 words and two images. That means, you have limited information and you have to start your investigation from there. The case file establishes that the person has expertise in Linguistics and Philosophy, that&amp;rsquo;s your &lt;em&gt;primary information&lt;/em&gt;. After that, the words are subtle and cryptic in their own rights, so, probably you can get the answers after reading further. In our case, that&amp;rsquo;s nothing but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://osintforall.in/ctf/case1/1/&#34;&gt;images&lt;/a&gt;, they look interesting, don&amp;rsquo;t they?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, you as an investigator need not to be a linguistic expert (even if you are, that&amp;rsquo;s great!), but here&amp;rsquo;s a text that you do not understand, what could you do? Translate? Sounds fair, but, if you had followed our &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AllForOsint&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or joined our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/2NN87XHc9A&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;, you would have known that I had said that &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to do with translation&amp;rdquo;, but, many of you got in the race of translating, finding historical references from N number of professors and so on. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m a lifelong history student, but did you really think that I&amp;rsquo;m going to create a CTF based on my biases? You got me wrong this time. Anyway, moving on, if not translation, what can you do? Comparison? Wow, wait what? With what? The answer is &amp;ldquo;Lorem Ipsum&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to get into the void of historical references or if some professor said something. Instead, “Just Google It!!” .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/unsolved1/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll get the organic results that generate “Lorem Ipsum” for you, as you already have the text written on the images, you could use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.onlineocr.net/&#34;&gt;online OCR&lt;/a&gt; to convert image to text or manually compare the Lorem generated text with the original. Then see the similarities. And you’ll find some differences and those differences are some names, which have already been cracked from our community members, Mary &amp;amp; Maas. How did they do that? Well, they used lots of their brain power to translate with different translators. And those translators did translate the text with some differences, as a result, differences could not translate the names to their epistemological origins and that’s how they got the names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll leave you here, and let me see if you can do something with those names and solve the case. If you want the names, an investigative partner or the community, join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/2NN87XHc9A&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; and participate in the discussions at #unsolvable-ctf. Good luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And also subscribe to our YouTube channel - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@osintforall&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/@osintforall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steganographic Tools For Beginners</title>
      <link>/articles/steganography/steganography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/steganography/steganography/</guid>
      <description>Hiding in plain sight has many dimensions. Sometimes, whatever you are looking for is before you, but you cannot see it; other times, it’s right before you but you don’t notice.
Steganography has been an art since the ancient days used to write hidden messages. It has evolved over the ages, and has changed form for the better. Nowadays we have software to hide and obfuscate messages. In this article, we’ll take a look at some amazing steganographic tools which are tiny yet powerful.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hiding in plain sight has many dimensions. Sometimes, whatever you
are looking for is before you, but you cannot see it; other times,
it’s right before you but you don’t notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steganography has been an art since the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steganography#History&#34;&gt;ancient&lt;/a&gt; days used to write
hidden messages. It has evolved over the ages, and has changed form
for the better. Nowadays we have software to hide and obfuscate
messages. In this article, we’ll take a look at some amazing
steganographic tools which are tiny yet powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;steghide&#34;&gt;Steghide&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steghide is one of the most popular steganographic tools out there.
It comes preinstalled in some of the GNU/Linux distributions. If
it’s not installed, you can download it from your package manager or
you can check their &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StefanoDeVuono/steghide&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It can hide data inside images and audio
files, it supports JPEG, BMP, WAV and AU formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s create a text file named secret.txt and try to hide it inside
an image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;steghide embed -cf yoda.jpg -ef secret.txt
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here -cf is cover file and -ef is embed file. The caveat is, you
should make sure your cover file is larger than your embed file,
that’s a no brainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s delete the secret.txt and see if we can extract it back
from the cover file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;steghide extract -sf yoda.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the -sf is stego file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our secret.txt is extracted. Wanna see what’s inside?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;strings&#34;&gt;Strings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s digress from the topic a bit. Strings is a command line tool
that helps to display printable strings in a file. In a sense, it’s
just like cat command. If you didn’t know already, now it’s a chance
to explore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;strings can be super helpful in steganographic challenges. For
instance, let’s say, a flag or password is embedded inside an image
file. And you have to match or put printable strings together in
order to solve the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cat out the file, you will end up with gibberish characters
printed out on to your screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat yoda.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/7.png&#34; alt=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas, if you use strings, you’ll get a bunch of strings with
printable characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;strings yoda.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among them, one of it might be your password or flag or a clue to
the next stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;exiftool&#34;&gt;Exiftool&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exif is a good place to hide your secret message. Exiftool helps to
view the information about metadata of images or files. Besides,
embedding secret messages, exif data could provide some juicy
information about the image, such as, geo coordinates, camera model,
creation date and so on. You can use simple tools like gThumb or
GIMP to edit medtadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;exiftool yoda.jpg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/9.png&#34; alt=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;binwalk&#34;&gt;Binwalk&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kali.org/tools/binwalk/&#34;&gt;Binwalk&lt;/a&gt; is a tool for searching binary images for embedded files and
executable code. It is actually a forensic tool, which helps to
analyse and audit binaries. It gives plenty of options to tinker
around binary files. Let’s see couple of options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have source code of a web page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just displays the embedded data in a given file.
If you want to extract the data from a binary, use -e flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/11.png&#34; alt=&#34;11&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file is extracted to _OpenShot-v2.6.1-x86_64.AppImage.extracted
folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/12.png&#34; alt=&#34;12&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wavsteg&#34;&gt;Wavsteg&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WavSteg is a tool written in Python, which can hide data in files
with a wav format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;stegolsb wavsteg -h -i piano.wav -s secret.txt -o stego.wav -n 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/13.png&#34; alt=&#34;13&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/14.png&#34; alt=&#34;14&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While extracting data, you have to specify the exact size of
embedded file(secret.txt) in bytes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/steganography/15.png&#34; alt=&#34;15&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;other-useful-resources&#34;&gt;Other Useful Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many online tools and professional software that could
facilitate steganography. Some of them are in the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dcode.fr/&#34;&gt;decode.fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.audacityteam.org/&#34;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Paradoxis/StegCracker&#34;&gt;StegCracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zed-0xff/zsteg&#34;&gt;Zsteg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/korczis/foremost&#34;&gt;Foremost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eugenekolo/sec-tools/tree/master/stego/stegsolve/stegsolve&#34;&gt;Stegsolve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sonicvisualiser.org/&#34;&gt;Sonic Visualiser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Power of IRC: Ultimate Guide to Information Gathering</title>
      <link>/articles/irc/irc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/irc/irc/</guid>
      <description>Internet Relay Chat (IRC) has long been a trusted platform for real-time text-based communication. But IRC is not just about chat; it offers a rich array of commands that can be harnessed for information gathering and efficient communication. In this comprehensive guide, we will explore the most valuable IRC commands for information gathering, along with the capabilities of the CTCP (Client-to-Client Protocol) commands. Prepare to embark on a journey of discovery as we unlock the hidden potential of IRC.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Internet Relay Chat (IRC) has long been a trusted platform for real-time text-based communication. But IRC is not just about chat; it offers a rich array of commands that can be harnessed for information gathering and efficient communication. In this comprehensive guide, we will explore the most valuable IRC commands for information gathering, along with the capabilities of the CTCP (Client-to-Client Protocol) commands. Prepare to embark on a journey of discovery as we unlock the hidden potential of IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;basics&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we move on to the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s learn some basics about IRC. What&amp;rsquo;s IRC? Is it like an app? Or a website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the core of IRC are servers, which host the IRC networks. These servers act as hubs, connecting users from different locations and facilitating communication between them. Each IRC network consists of multiple servers linked together, forming a vast network of interconnected nodes. Generally, in the context of IRC, the names &amp;lsquo;IRC servers&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;IRC Networks&amp;rsquo; are used interchangeably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users connect to an IRC server using an IRC client (Irssi, Hexchat), which is software that allows individuals to interact with the IRC network. The client provides a user-friendly interface through which users can join channels, send messages, and participate in discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channels are virtual spaces within the IRC network where users can gather and engage in conversations on specific topics. Channels are denoted by a &amp;ldquo;#&amp;rdquo; symbol followed by a unique name, such as &amp;ldquo;#osintforall&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;#programming&amp;rdquo;. Users can join channels of interest to connect with like-minded individuals, share knowledge, and discuss various subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/server1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users join a channel, they can send messages to the channel that are visible to all participants. These messages can be seen and responded to in real-time. Users can also send private messages to other individuals on the network, allowing for one-on-one conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;analogy&#34;&gt;Analogy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to imagine Discord “servers”, where we join a server, for example, Osint For All server, and we can join individual channels there. Even though we can do a lot of other things on Discord compared to IRC, the idea behind it is somewhat the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One advantage of IRC over Discord is that we don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to register to a server and join channels, whereas in Discord, we need to create an account first, and then we can join and chat on different servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;irc-clients&#34;&gt;IRC Clients&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An IRC client is a software application that allows users to connect to and interact with IRC servers. It serves as the interface between the user and the IRC network, enabling them to participate in real-time text-based conversations, join channels, and perform various actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRC clients come in different forms, including standalone desktop applications, web-based clients, and command line clients. They provide a user-friendly interface that simplifies the process of connecting to an IRC server and navigating the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommendations are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irssi (Command line)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hexchat (GUI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/clients.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-the-ground-opsec-tips&#34;&gt;Setting The Ground (Opsec Tips)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For demonstration purposes, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using Irssi client and connecting to Libera Chat network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the above image, we have connected to Libera Chat server/network. And the text enclosed in the red rectangle is the nickname which was set previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to conceal ourselves, we can change, &lt;em&gt;real_name&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hostname&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nickname&lt;/em&gt; in Irssi by using /set command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see from the above image, we have changed our &lt;em&gt;real_name&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hostname&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nickname&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Ultrachad&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;information-gathering-commands&#34;&gt;Information Gathering Commands&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.WHOIS: The WHOIS command allows us to retrieve detailed information about a specific user, including their nickname, username, hostname, real name, server information, and channels they are currently in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage: /whois &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/4.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see from the above image, using /whois, we have gathered some basic information about a user named amoghavarsha(&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TheAmoghavarsha&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s me!&lt;/a&gt;). And remember, we haven&amp;rsquo;t logged in as a user yet, but we can still just connect to a server and gather basic information about users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to log in, we can use &lt;em&gt;/msg nickserv identify amoghavarsha &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/em&gt; command as shown in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/5.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we login, we can also use &lt;em&gt;cloak&lt;/em&gt; provided by Libera chat, by joining #libera-cloak and typing !cloakme. Cloaks/Cloaking helps us to conceal our IP address and replace that with something random depending on the servers/networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/6.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.WHOWAS: The WHOWAS command allows us to retrieve detailed information about a specific user, including their nickname, username, hostname, real name, server information that they might have had previously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see in the image below, when we search for a user named &lt;em&gt;john&lt;/em&gt; we got their previous records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/8.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, in our example, we got some other extra information about the user &lt;em&gt;john&lt;/em&gt; apart from their previous connections. Here we can see a new IP address that &lt;em&gt;john&lt;/em&gt; could have connected, and we can also presume that &lt;em&gt;john&lt;/em&gt; might be using &lt;strong&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/strong&gt; email client. These cannot be confirmed unless we do a physical forensic test, which is not in the interest of this guide, but with intuition there is a strong chance that they might be using Thunderbird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.LIST: The LIST command provides an overview of channels on the server, along with their topics and the number of users in each channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see in the images below, we have listed all the channels in the Libera chat server (A-Z), we use &lt;em&gt;-y&lt;/em&gt; flag in Irssi to confirm to a huge list of all channels in the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/10.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/11.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.JOIN: The JOIN command enables us to join a specific channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As seen in the image below, let&amp;rsquo;s join #python channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/12.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s something interesting to notice, when we joined the channel, we can see that our IP address is hidden, and it&amp;rsquo;s replaced instead &lt;em&gt;user/Amoghavarsha&lt;/em&gt;. So these are some advantages of having an account and also cloaking that we discussed earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/13.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.NAMES: The NAMES command gives us the (nick)names of all the users in a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see in the image below, we got a lot of names from the python group. Joining certain groups to investigate a target is one of the best ways to track their activities. Having an insight/intuition about target&amp;rsquo;s preferred channels is useful. It could be guessed by tracking their online activities on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/14.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/15.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.WHO: The WHO command is similar to WHOIS, but in brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we can see in the image below, we just searched for a random user from #python group nicked &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt;, in order to get basic information. And luckily we got their presumably the real name (Jim Ramsay) and their email (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:i.am@jimramsay.com&#34;&gt;i.am@jimramsay.com&lt;/a&gt;), in turn their website (jimramsay.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/16.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, when we did check for /WHOIS and /WHOWAS records, we got some juicy information such as their last login and the channels that they are active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/17.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/16.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.MODE: The MODE command displays or changes the mode of a user or channel, allowing control over various aspects such as channel moderation, user permissions, and channel settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here in the image below, when we check the MODE of python channel, we got some basic information such as date of the channel creation, the person who set the topic and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/18.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/19.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.MOTD: The MOTD command displays the &amp;lsquo;Message of the day&amp;rsquo; on the server, generally set by the admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the image below, we can see the MOTD of Libera Chat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/24.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;niche-area&#34;&gt;Niche Area&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we have covered some basic information gathering commands, let&amp;rsquo;s try to look at another command and its variations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.CTCP: CTCP stands for &amp;lsquo;Client to client protocol&amp;rsquo;, which tries to provide some basic information about target&amp;rsquo;s clients and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; &amp;lt;COMAMND&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the image below, when we got some information about &lt;em&gt;lack&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s client by using CTCP VERSION command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; VERSION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/22.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CTCP VERSION command retrieves the client version of a user, revealing the IRC client software they are using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, when we tried using CTCP TIME command on another nick &lt;em&gt;(lexandrop)&lt;/em&gt;, we got the following result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; TIME&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/irc/25.png&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CTCP TIME command requests the local time of a user&amp;rsquo;s IRC client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;some-interesting-ctcp-commands&#34;&gt;Some Interesting CTCP Commands&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some CTCP commands that are interesting, perhaps they don’t necessarily guarantee the result. This is because, as we are in 2023, IRC clients have improved a lot, and some old school IRC commands have become obsolete. But, we’ll never know what we can get, so that’s why I’m going to explain some CTCP commands that are worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTCP PING: The CTCP PING command measures the round-trip time (RTT) between our client and the target user&amp;rsquo;s client, providing an indication of network latency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; PING&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTCP ACTION: The CTCP ACTION command allows us to send an action or emote to a user or channel, expressing an emotion or describing an action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; ACTTION&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CTCP CLIENTINFO: The CTCP CLIENTINFO command requests information about the CTCP commands supported by a user&amp;rsquo;s IRC client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usuage: /CTCP &amp;lt;NICKNAME&amp;gt; CLIENTINFO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bottleneck&#34;&gt;Bottleneck&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot enter private #servers / #networks without permission or an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot enter private #channels without permission or an invite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admins can kick or ban you anytime with or without notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your IP could be blocked by the admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bottomline&#34;&gt;Bottomline&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this comprehensive guide, we have explored a wide range of IRC commands for information gathering and CTCP commands for enhanced communication experiences. By mastering these commands, we can unlock the true potential of IRC, whether it&amp;rsquo;s discovering valuable information, engaging in meaningful conversations, or troubleshooting technical issues. Embrace the power of IRC, and let its commands be our gateway to a world of knowledge, connections, and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;important-links&#34;&gt;Important Links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start using IRC (&lt;a href=&#34;https://hexchat.github.io/&#34;&gt;Hexchat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://irssi.org/&#34;&gt;Irssi&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mirc.com/servers.html&#34;&gt;https://www.mirc.com/servers.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ntUjftZ-9Jg&#34;&gt;How to use Irssi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/pJSDglguaGE&#34;&gt;How to set up a GUI IRC Client &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/jsXvCKuetWU&#34;&gt;IRC Bouncers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat&#34;&gt;IRC Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When You Cannot Solve A Geolocation Challenge In 24 Hours...</title>
      <link>/articles/geo/geo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/geo/geo/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago I posted an image (the original image is distorted by heavy color grading) as a part of the Osint geolocation challenge on Discord &amp;amp; Twitter. Many people tried it, but they couldn’t solve the challenge in 24 hours, even the 2-10 minute geoguessers failed I presume! (And probably, most of you didn’t even get to know about it, sorry folks, curse algorithms, follow us on Twitter - @AllForOsint!</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/articles/geo/2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few days ago I posted an image (the original image is distorted by heavy color grading) as a part of the Osint geolocation challenge on Discord &amp;amp; Twitter. Many people tried it, but they couldn’t solve the challenge in 24 hours, even the 2-10 minute geoguessers failed I presume! (And probably, most of you didn’t even get to know about it, sorry folks, curse algorithms, follow us on Twitter - @AllForOsint!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’m not going to write a walk through about the image, instead I’ll try to point out why you could not solve the challenge and what are the things that you have to keep in mind when solving a geolocation challenge. I also believe that if someone is claiming to teach you how to solve the any geolocation challenge, they would be lying to you if they don’t provide the perspectives that I’m providing in this article. So buckle up and get ready for a long ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;geolocation-challenges&#34;&gt;Geolocation Challenges&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geolocation challenges are the way to improvise your geolocating skills through the means of free to use softwares such as Google Maps, Google Earth, Zoom Earth and so on. All these tools are useless if there is no human knowledge associated with them (at least before the AI revolution goes mainstream!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to geolocate anything, you need not to have a large set of tools apart from the aforementioned tools, rather you need to know the &lt;strong&gt;Encyclopedia&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait what? Encyclopedia? Yes, you heard that right. Whether it’s a &lt;em&gt;location&lt;/em&gt; or an &lt;em&gt;object&lt;/em&gt; the encyclopedia got you covered. Do you remember those world encyclopedias with more than 1000 pages lying in our school libraries? And the kids who used to read those were considered as geeks/nerds/bookworms; ring any bells?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What these encyclopedias consisted of was the A-Z knowledge about the world in general. Depending on the topics, they used to cover everything from culture to cuisines, hieroglyphs to history, geography to geopolitics, politics to permanent records and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, you don’t have to go through all the encyclopedias if you don’t want to, because you have the Internet. You can learn everything from the Internet at your fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;reality-of-geoguessr&#34;&gt;Reality Of Geoguessr&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one of the recent interviews with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0p5Eb4OSZCs&#34;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;, Rainbolt, a pro geoguessr mentions that he had spent around 13 months studying countries and he’s still learning about few other countries such as India to be able to geolocate in those landscapes. Well, this is true. This is what I was talking about when I told you about the importance of world encyclopedia. Just by solving some region specific or your echo chamber specific locations doesn’t make you any pro. You are one among all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to pursue a career as a Geoguesser, you have to spend months or years to practice and remember all the open source geo knowledge out there and that could also mean that it’s dynamic - landscapes change, people migrate, new buildings might raise and so on, you should also adapt to those changes. And most importantly, there has to be a proper job market for that (Seems like it is taking off).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;problemparable-of-parallel-construction&#34;&gt;Problem/Parable Of Parallel Construction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already made a funny video on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0taM8rwGsI&#34;&gt;parallel construction&lt;/a&gt;, you can go and watch that on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCe4w3wDp6-NqaRZWstpuqYg/videos&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;. To simplify, parallel construction is something where you arrive at a destination in prior and construct a story about how you arrived there. And this story could be true/false/convenient to you/your narrative. When you hear about a parable of 1 second geoguessr challenge, you might wonder if it is some kind of superpower, but what if the geo guessing location was the same street that the dude/dudine walks around everyday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could have both positive and negative effects on your learning process. The parable of awesomeness and encouragement is good, but the false notion of making it look simpler is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;anyone-can-geolocate---love-your-culture&#34;&gt;Anyone Can Geolocate - Love Your Culture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably it’s easier for someone who grew up on the shoulders of Silicon Valley to geolocate Apple Park or Meta’s headquarters than someone sitting in Alaska. Likewise, your country/state/district/region/area is your strength. Because you know them well, if you don’t know, stop reading this article, get out and explore! I’m not saying that you’ll be able to record everything in your visual memory, but at least you’ll have an idea where to look further if it turns out to be wrong. You are constantly getting influenced by your surroundings and culture, whether it’s social media, local news channels, news papers, something that your friend posted on Instagram when she visited a nearby city etc., could be helpful for you someday to gather some information or find a clue about your region. So keep your eyes &amp;amp; ears open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;verification-is-hard&#34;&gt;Verification Is Hard&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirming images, dates, time and verifying locations is not always bed of roses, even if you are a pro. You have to admit your limitations, you cannot strongly remember everything. Sometimes, good journalists&#39; spend several nights/months to verify facts and sometimes that might go wrong as well! Beware of mirages, there could be similar looking locations but might not be the exact location that you would be looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if I asked you what will happen to Zhouzhuang after 50 years, will you be able to answer without Googling or knowing anything about it? Probably not.
So this brings us to the limitations of geolocation challenges. You can only get an opportunity to collate the intelligence of what&amp;rsquo;s already there or what’s already known. If Google maps removes some areas from its database, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably never know how to or where to get clear visual information about those areas. So the companies/spy agencies that have control over hoarding data and making them available for the public to hoard more data are a deadly combination of convenience and crookedness. And depending on the country that you live, categorically, developed nations would have more discoverable areas, developing countries a bit less and underdeveloped a bit lesser relatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;humint-matters&#34;&gt;Humint Matters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend in need is a friend in deed; but if they are international, then you are fortunate.
Even though data giants have a lot of power to invest in data hoarding, sometimes, everything cannot be collected and distributed, the first reason being the world is too big of a place and the second is all thanks to the god of chaos/randomness. In order to avoid fault lines or the data that’s blurry, having Human Intelligence is vital. But it comes with the cost of FUD. Not always and not because your friend has ill intentions, possibly they might not have the intentions or talent or interest that you are asking for. Having friends with similar interests is a gift, never lose them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;black-spots&#34;&gt;Black Spots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have watched some movies or TV shows, where spies meet at a rendezvous possibly would be a black spot. Even on the Internet, there are lots and lots of black spots where you cannot penetrate or you don’t have the necessary tools to facilitate that! And it’s OKAY. When there’s some new discovery by other people who have dedicated their lives to uncover that blackspot or solve that bottleneck, you’ll know, appreciate them and bookmark that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;knowledge-space&#34;&gt;Knowledge Space&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do I get all this knowledge? By spending 8 hours a day on Google Maps? Ah, no I don’t have time for that, and I can’t sit in front of a computer for too long. Will I ever be able to become a GOAT?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is ‘Depends’. I cannot guarantee you if you can become a GOAT or not, but I can give you some tips where you can get the knowledge in an unconventional or upbeat manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch movies, TV shows, research about them and their accuracy. Learn a new language, try to watch videos of different languages, read travel blogs and watch travel vlogs, play games related to geoguessr, follow climate news, follow social media pages related to local and international cuisines; do whatever you can to make the world as your playground with publicly available data. And also never undermine the aspect of luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do all these things, depending on your interests or job requirement or just as a hobby. And, here comes the bummer - &lt;em&gt;You don’t have to do that all the time&lt;/em&gt;. Because &lt;strong&gt;time is precious, waste it wisely.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;wisdom-of-the-crowd&#34;&gt;Wisdom Of The Crowd&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have come this far, you would have probably understood, why couldn’t you solve the challenge. Because it DEPENDS ON MANY THINGS, AND EVERYONE CANNOT BE EVERYWHERE AND KNOW EVERYTHING ELSE. One of our goals at &lt;strong&gt;Osint For All&lt;/strong&gt; is to empower/motivate every Internet user to make them knowledgeable about technologies that are widespread and publicly available. Everyone has their own intrinsic value, everyone has their own share in this web called as the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for today, hope you liked the article. So please&amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subscibe - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@osintforall&#34;&gt;Osint For All&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@linuxforall_&#34;&gt;Linux For All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/allforosint&#34;&gt;Osint For All&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/linuxforall_&#34;&gt;Linux For All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit - &lt;a href=&#34;https://osintforall.in/&#34;&gt;https://osintforall.in/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donate - &lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/osintforall&#34;&gt;https://ko-fi.com/osintforall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
